Today, I'm going to start with the...
Just give me a minute.
All right, okay.
I hope you can see my screen and this is
my, if you have any issues,
just let me know.
I think we are pretty much covered. Yeah,
let's get this started.
Welcome to our first session on Software
Product Management. I see your profiles,
I see most of the people have experience.
What's the average experience? I can see,
is it like...
What's your average?
I just want to understand what type of
audience I'm teaching, you know,
what type of audience.
I don't want to treat you as a junior or
a fresh out of college. I see, yeah,
I can see a lot of good experiences.
Can I just roughly see three plus years
experience? Thank you. Thank you.
Nine years, Samir.
Yep, thank you, Jain.
Great, thank you, Abhinav. Yep, thank you,
thank you, thank you. That's amazing.
So I just want to know, like,
how do I structure my program?
I don't want to go basics and tell you
guys,
I know you would have seen in your index
to experience all this.
So thank you very much. I have a C,
an average of five years of experience
with all this, if you take it onto it.
four to five years experience.
So I need to structure my program
accordingly.
I need to start delivering my lectures
based on the experience or do you have it.
So I don't want to go and just teach your
basic fundamentals on it.
All right, my name is MADHU VENKAT.
Let me introduce myself.
My name is Madhu VENKAT.
I'm based out of Chennai right now.
I was born and brought up in Chennai,
then moved to Bangalore.
I did my college masters in computer
science and started my career in...
But 25 plus years experience over here
before after college masters.
I have close to 25 plus years of
experience in software industry and 20
plus years of product management and
development experience.
And all of all my 20 years I've been
building products for oil and gas,
healthcare, domain expert, hospitality.
finance, many domains, verticals,
but these are three verticals where I
spent all my major part of my experience
of 20 years, oil and gas, healthcare,
hospitality domains. So.
Right, 10 years, close out of 20 years,
I've been always focusing on building
products for global markets,
not only for India.
My major part of my experience is on
North America. Today, I'm right now,
my company I work,
I work as a managing director for Asia
back regions where I build products for
hospitality and...
Thing which I we cover close to about 30
plus thirty-five plus countries, so...
And the base Rd.
development set is based on India,
so that's my background.
And for all my experiences,
what the session is going to be more of
my experiences where on a day-to-day
experience,
how I deal with what kind of experiences
I've gained in the last 25 years.
I'll be trying my best to share all those
experiences with you.
Since I see you have amazing experience
of crowd.
13, 15, 10, 5. I love,
I know that you also have solid
experience on building products,
building projects and all that.
I'd love to hear your thoughts.
You can add,
let's make it more interactive.
I don't want to be a bit one directional.
If it's more bidirectional,
it'll be more interesting.
Feel free to unmute yourself and feel
free to share your experience with us.
It will be with this crowd.
It will be great.
It will be a great learning experience
for each one of you. I'm learning still,
even though I come from 25 years
experience,
what I saw 25 years back today,
the tools and technologies and the
process.
We don't follow today the same process,
the same tools, same technologies.
So every year,
every day is a new day for software
industry, when you work in industry.
Even yesterday is new, old, it's become,
that's the kind of rapid development
things happening in the industry.
Even though I have 25 year experience,
if you see me, still I'm new.
I'm learning every day new things and
everything is a new. Every process is new.
Customers' problems are new nowadays.
People don't ask the same problem what 24
years back.
Customers don't ask what 25 years back
they asked today.
They don't ask the same problem.
to solve.
Every day is a new problem to solve.
every day.
They think about next five years
futuristic.
So today we don't talk about what's today
probably.
We're talking about how is it going to be
happen in the last 10 years,
next 10 years.
What changes are going to come to it?
That is where I've seen in my experiences.
We should be, I think people say,
if you are born, you have the...
This is the best time to be born and
working in a software industry.
Even though AI is displacing,
bringing up major changes to it,
even though that,
but the best time to be born and work in
the industry, software industry is,
this is the best time to be in.
And if you are experienced,
you love technology, if you work,
your hands-on engineer.
I think this is the best time to be
around.
Right, uh, I think uh,
so this is the first semester.
Yeah,
this is our first semester in IM Tech.
We know we have a software development
for a specialist,
so we will be spending long time.
Absolutely, Abhinav. We will be.
What I meant to say is,
even though I called myself with an
experience,
but I'm trying to learn every day,
this is what I'm going to come with it.
Out of this crowd,
is anyone working as a product manager,
product owner?
Is anyone working as a product owner or a
product manager? Okay, ANKUR MITTAL,
thank you.
I'm sure you would have seen all this.
Thank you, thank you, ANKUR.
All right,
so I see one person works on a real time
this crowd who was working on a real time
on Product Management.
So I'm sure probably ANKUR I need to
pitch in some time to get your thoughts
on this also.
So let's make it more interactive from
your experience. All right, let's.
Let's get on to it.
This is my experience and let's move on
to understand. See,
there will be some slides will be.
I'm trying my best to cover some
practical experiences,
realistic experiences, wherever it is.
Sometimes those realistic experience may
not be specified in the slides,
but I'll be sharing.
orally what experience I went through it.
So.
Sometimes if you feel it's more of theory,
you know,
Software Product Management is all about,
it's nothing to do with experience.
Building a product is the real experience,
but these are concepts and understanding
of how,
what is the Software Product Management
and how it all evolves and what is the...
role of a product manager in the company
is all what we're going to talk about.
All right. Okay,
today what we're going to talk about,
there are a lot of topics we'll be
covering today,
but I just want to go touch base all
these on a fundamental level.
So in a forthcoming sessions,
we'll be going in detail,
understanding about one by one,
the link down.
in detail understanding about all that.
Today we're going to talk about why a
product manager is required. You know,
what is a product management?
Product Management life cycle is what is
product and life cycle?
Understanding of customers.
What is product discovery versus delivery?
Writing,
what is the user story we know all about?
Prioritization.
What are the roadmap releases?
Measuring product concepts, success.
So these are very high level concepts
we'll be touching upon today.
The reason why I'm trying to cover all
this is as you move forward on the class
sessions,
we'll be more in detail talking about
these things more. You know,
the techniques of product management,
techniques of...
You know, user story writing. What are,
how do you prioritize it?
What kind of techniques available in the
industry to prioritize your requirements?
How do you plan your roadmaps?
How do you plan your releases?
So a lot of in-depth knowledge, you know,
analysis and learnings we'll be doing.
As we move forward,
so today I'll be just covering about
starting a basic of what is a product
management, why do we need it,
what's a life cycle of a product
management, and how do we, what life,
how do we understand a customers,
then product discovery and delivery and
user stories?
Okay.
All right, now.
Let's get on to why product management.
Okay,
I'm sure I just want to jump into it. So,
ANKUR,
I'm going to pitch in and ask you all
this so that you don't feel embarrassed
and all. Let's make it more interesting.
So, from your point of view,
do you see why you want to define why?
Why do we need product management in the
industry?
If you can unmute yourself, we can...
Or you can type it,
whichever you feel better.
Why do you need product management?
Is anyone can share why do you need
product management in a company,
in a software company,
or any product companies,
where do you need it?
Muted. Oh, okay. I'm so sorry. I'll...
Okay, got it. Let me, let me. How come?
Yeah, ANKUR have enabled it. Okay,
so I have a,
I think I need to go back and just give
me a minute.
Yeah, yeah, thank you. Hi, everyone.
Like, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, so, yeah,
so answering to the first question,
I guess,
like product management is the core of
from designing product and delivery,
right?
So it's basically the main funda is to
deliver the right product for right
customers. So that is the crux I can say.
Perfect. Perfect.
To deliver the right product for the
right customer.
That's a right definition of it in a
single line.
Right product for the right customer.
Let's assume you're a wire product
command. In a simple example I would take,
let's assume you're a CEO for Swiggy.
You're a customer.
Your customers have given about your
feedback about your Swiggy app. Add more,
add more veg dishes.
Your mobile app is slow.
Your full delivery takes too long.
Introduce loyalty points.
My area is not covered.
There are about 20 to 100.
feedback points which be shared to you as
a CEO of a VIVEK.
Now you have only one month time you have
you have a small developer team.
What will you build first out of these
points?
Let's say have four points I've added,
add more veg dishes, your app is slow,
your delivery food delivery takes too
long, introduce loyalty points.
Out of this four feedback,
which is the one thing as a CEO you'll be
focusing on?
Alright,
your app is slow as it affects more
customers. Yes.
Yes, that's one thing. Your app is more...
Yes.
Yeah, yeah.
What is the second thing you'll be
focusing on?
Yep, yep.
Correct. I think 100%.
I think pretty much we'll be covering
more on fastest out of this four.
Your app is slow is the worst most
important thing because that's going to
affect all your customers. Your customer,
that's a major value,
you're going to impact your business in
this case. Your app,
your customers are going to leave out
your app and they're going to switch to
your competitor because your app is
pretty slow. They're not able to.
place an order.
That's the highest problem you need to
focus on to get this fixed. Second,
you're a food delivery app, right?
Your business main business model is
delivery, food delivery.
And if your food delivery sticks too long,
still, again,
it doesn't serve your business. Again,
you're losing.
to your competitor or your customers are
not going to be happy with that because
the one reason he's coming to you as
Swiggy to one is you're able to get the
food within the time given,
committed time which you give it to him.
Right? So yes,
so the point which you will be focusing
more on is.
Your mobile app is slow.
Second is food delivery takes too long.
The other things, add more veg dishes,
introduce loyalty points. These are good,
but it's not.
very important today.
The burning issue in this case,
or the fourth thing is,
as a CEO of a Swiggy,
you'd be more focusing on getting the
second issue fixed,
your mobile app is slow. Second,
your food delivery takes too long.
These are very important problems to
solve today.
This is a job of a product manager today
on a day-to-day basis.
A lot of requests comes from product.
As ANKUR has rightly said, what product,
right product for the right customer?
You know, like as he said,
are we developing,
he'll be focusing on the right feature.
Are we developing the right feature?
Are we solving the right problem?
That's the job of a Product Management.
So as a CEO of a Swiggy or any company,
you'll be forgetting all the requests
from various sites.
You need to spend your resources.
You have a limited resources in your hand.
You have a limited budget in your hand.
And you have to focus on what you can
address with a limited budget. Today,
what's the problem which you can,
this mobile app slow is going to help you
out to immediate satisfaction customers
where you'll improve the satisfaction
level of a customers. They come,
they order. Second is food delivery.
When they come at.
They get, they are going to deliver,
the food is going to be delivered within
the time period given to them.
That way they have satisfaction.
The add dishes, loyalty point,
they'll be happy. Yes, they're happy.
They'll be happy. Out of 100 customers,
maybe 5 customers expects you veg dishes
more. The rest all are happy.
You're happy with that. You know, okay,
you may lose five or six customers.
For now, today, you're okay.
But imagine this app, mobile app,
and food delivery is a major problem,
covering about 100% of the customers.
So you need to focus on that. So as a CEO,
you only are developing this,
you'll be focusing on the most important
problem, what you have today.
Let's assume in a simple organizing party
for your customer.
Everyone acts like a product manager
today.
in a day-to-day life. You agree? Everyone,
today, everyone is a product manager.
As a product,
you're doing a product management on a
day-to-day basis on various scenarios and
various situations in life. Say,
let's say organizing parties for your
friends. What are your prioritize? One is.
Must have, you need a great music,
amazing drinks, in case you are,
you got a great food, snacks,
best place to sit and eat, right?
That's the most important thing.
You're not looking for,
you're not getting a phone booth,
signature drink, goodies, and all.
That's a priority.
That's not a top priority for you.
To give a best experience, the top three,
4 priorities,
what you would give is great music.
and you're going to give an amazing drink
in case you have a drink.
If you're going to include in your party,
go to grade up amazing food, spicy,
or whatever the food you love,
your audience, your friends like it,
and you're going to have enough place,
a beautiful ambience for them so that
they can have an amazing space for them
to enjoy the party. That's a must.
You know, those are the must-have feature,
which is non-negotiable features,
non-negotiable things which you need to
take care when you organize a party.
Second thing should have.
If time permits,
you love to enhance it by adding main
course, pizza, tacos,
and fun group activities, party games,
and probably gonna have coverage.
Could have, okay, right? You have budget,
you have a time,
you can bring in some party flavors and
bring some signature drink and all.
And out of scope is basically schedule of
forced activities, three course dinner,
all that. These are not must.
The must have is the most to make your
party most successful.
The must have is non-negotiable of music,
amazing drinks, amazing foods,
a beautiful place to enjoy. You agree?
So the point is, yeah,
this is where you focus your,
as a product manager, you focus your,
prioritize it. As a, as a,
we all are product managers on a
day-to-day basis in our life.
We all prioritize our priorities.
We decide what we want in life.
Let's say you are a product manager for
your life today.
You can spend your weekend,
Saturday and Sundays, doing partying,
going for a trip, enjoying,
going for all the sleep, all that.
But you prioritize.
In your life, getting into WILP program,
enrolling into WILP program,
joining and taking a MTech program is
going to help you to go to the next level
in your career.
So you're a solid project manager.
You had a lot of priorities.
You had a parties, you know,
which a must-have is you decided, okay,
let me choose this as my must-have
because that's going to help you.
Me to create a more impact in my life.
Right?
So we all act as a product manager on a
day-to-day basis. That's the same thing.
Out of all things items which are excites
us, which is a should we focus on?
Which problem should we solve?
Which is the right product,
right problem to solve for the customers?
or customer.
That's why we need a product management
in a company or in any part of the
organization.
Anyone wants to give a better example
than this? So feel free to.
You can raise your hands. I can unmute.
I need to. I can do that.
Do you have any other better examples?
Also, you can feel free to do it.
Okay,
so let's say we understand why we need a
product manager. Basically, as ANKUR said,
building a right product for the right
customer. That's it.
Nothing more than that. Right product.
Are we right of solving the right problem?
For our right customers,
that's the job of a product management.
OK,
so I think this is would have given you
an idea of what is a product management
with this example of acting as a CEO of a
Swiggy. OK.
The problem every company faces is which
problems should be solved,
which features should be built,
which requests should wait.
This is very challenging. You know,
today I manage,
we have a product which we cater to
product hospitality industry. We have 30,
44,800 customers around the world.
We have both 35 plus countries.
We get requests,
requirement changes coming from all most
of our customers saying I need this
feature, I need that feature.
It's a very tough challenge.
Every day we do roadmap analysis.
Which feature should we focus for this
release? Every month we do 2 releases,
one is major release and one minor
release.
Every month we try to sit through it.
We capture all the requirements which are
coming from all the major part of
customers we capture into our Jira board
or a ticket or it could be Zoho tickets
comes in.
And every Monday we go through all the
requests coming in and we try to analyze,
is this,
should we fix this on this release?
Should we keep it?
Maybe out of 100 customers,
10 customers or 50 customers ask for the
same problem. They have,
they raised us the same problem.
We are going to focus that.
to fix it. That's one criteria.
Second criteria, if the customer says,
this feature, if you bring in,
it'll get a lot of value for other
customers.
We see a big value for other customers
also because there's a new feature a new
customer brings in using AI analysis,
basically a forecasting model with AI.
He wants it.
And we see other customers never asked it,
but this customer has asked for it.
We will try to analyze and see when you
add this feature,
will it add value to our product,
value to our customers, other customers?
Then we prioritize to give more
importance to that.
Third,
if some huge sales or business waiting to
close by sales team and they say without
this feature,
the customer is not ready to close the
order.
We try to prioritize to that to close
that particular feature.
And there are some pending things which a
customer says, without this,
I can't pay you money.
So there's a lot of permutation
combinations,
ifs and buts we take to decide, okay,
which problems should be solved.
Got it? You can only act for yourself.
There are a lot of things matters.
You know,
your cash flow has to be maintained.
Your competitors has to be thought
through.
Your sales teams comes up with a
different pressure.
A lot of things comes in.
You need to really think through it and
see how to utilize your resources.
So that which problem to solve?
You have hundreds of problems to solve,
but you have only 20 engineers available
in your hand,
and you have a limited time to fix and
release it.
How to prioritize your problems in such a
way,
utilize your 20 resources engineers
effectively.
So which problems should be solved is
very, very important.
We spend more amount of time as a product
managers, senior leadership team,
they spend in time in what problem to
solve.
That is where the major part of our time
goes on, on every releases.
And which features should be built?
A lot of under features every customers
comes and says problems are different,
features are different,
problems will be like they are saying one
problem with e-invoicing,
invoice printout is not happening. Okay,
customer says invoice when he takes a
copy of when he generates a invoice it
goes to a.
GST update,
GST bill calculation is not properly
calculated, taxes not calculated. Okay,
the customers keep complaining,
says this is a very important compliance
issue,
so we have to focus on that to get that
resolved. Okay, that's a problem to solve.
Features are different.
Let's say today one company.
We focus on hospitality.
We are exploring humanoid robots,
you know, humanoid robots where you see,
have you seen any restaurants where
robotic robots, womanoid robots,
they come and deliver food?
Have you seen any of the restaurants you
have been there?
Have you seen any of the robots coming on,
small robots which just comes and
delivers your food to the table?
When you place an order,
automatically it comes in,
it comes and delivers.
I'm sure the humanoid robots are slowly,
yes, some restaurants, yes.
A lot of it's slowly catching up.
You know, it's
heard about that, not experienced it.
It's really catching up actually.
If you see that, I can, it's,
they come and deliver you based on it,
it automatically comes and delivers to
your table. It knows when the kitchen,
they'll, you place an order,
the kitchen prepares a food and the human
aid robots goes there.
fix the order,
the key in saying do not do table number
12 and automatically knows where the
table number 12 is in the whole dining
room and it just comes and delivers to
you.
You know why?
These are basically trying to reduce the
cost, labor's cost.
These are futuristic restaurants which
are coming onto it.
So today we have a features we want to
develop. Yes, we want to develop.
These are features we want to develop so
that our product can be more advanced and
can look forward for the next 10 years
how the technology is going to be. So
These are a very important job of a
product manager. He has to,
it's a very one of the interesting job.
The first job is product manager's job in
the company.
It's not the engineer job,
it's not the other,
it is not that I'm saying other jobs are.
Not as.
dfdf.
But the product manager's job is...
Very responsible job,
because he is the one who decides.
what problem to solve,
what features to add to the product so
that it can bring in more revenue,
it can have a more business impact for
your business,
it can satisfy your customers more.
He all goes with his intuition.
So product manager's job plays a very
vital role in any product companies.
You know,
whether you work for a Google or Amazon
or when even for Tesla.
Tesla is like major part of product
management is all handled by Elon Musk.
You know,
he decides what features to go and what
he decides.
It's his dream car, it's his dream share,
it's all product manager's job. You know,
that's the key.
They are the highest paid person in a
major part of the company as a product
companies because they are the CEO of the
product. They decide,
they set the vision for the product. Okay,
so hope you all understand what a product
means.
Manager, let's go into it.
Yes,
so we have built a robot like that for
pharmaceutical laboratory. Oh, Mike, okay.
Well, pundit, that's amazing.
Every product is also replaced by a robot
in future.
Okay, are not sure if it is good or not.
My jobs are jobs going out of the waiters.
All right,
our waiters are more expensive then. Okay,
I see waiters are more expensive robots.
See,
I think that is Vanishka Jain has asked
this question.
Are waiters are more expensive than the
robots? In countries like US.
In countries like Japan,
in countries where a developed country,
labors are very expensive.
You don't have labors like how you get in
India and China or Pakistan.
In those countries,
people can't rely on labors,
day-to-day labors. You know,
India has a population,
so we have advantage of it.
Companies like North America and other
countries, they
would have prefer going with these kind
of technologies.
They are the one who bring in revolutions,
but this because of the limitation,
the constraint they have on the resources,
like how not we don't have.
We have all this advantage of having
laborers and population,
so we are able to get maids and be able
to get this lib.
Waiters at a fraction of cost,
which is impossible. So, future Italy,
they are saying how to replace all these
waiters with the robotics, you know,
human robots.
That is a major thing coming up,
and so that is every OK.
That is hope that answers your question.
Seems like a one-time investment robots,
yes.
One time you invest,
you can have hundreds of waiters.
Waiters don't complain about, you waiters,
human waiters,
they come and complain about loyalty,
they need extra time, they are not well,
they are sick today, they can't,
they're feeling where they don't smile
properly,
they give a irritating response to
customers.
Whereas robot doesn't do all that,
you can deliver 1000 times,
you can send and deliver to the same
table,
you can go and do it without any problem.
You agree? That is one thing.
I see that every product,
Neeraj Kumar RAJ has asked this question,
even a product manager is also a
replacement robot in future.
See, every product manager,
even a robot is designed by a product
manager. A product manager is very,
how do we say,
a product manager can be replaced? Yes.
How AI is replacing is basically,
now if you see this AI today,
we have used,
I was in an era where I never had any AI.
Today I worked in,
I'm using AI in a day-to-day basis in our
company and organization.
What has changed from last 10 years
before and today what has changed is the
speed of discovery, the speed of analysis,
the speed of trying to solve a problem
using AI like Cloud or...
You know, Chat GPTs or Gen.
AIs and use these tools.
It helps me to discover the problem
faster and solving the problem faster
than what it used to take 10 years back.
Right? That is a major breakthrough of AI.
So I won't say we'll go to replace these
robots as a product managers.
The product managers are going to be more
intelligent and they become more,
they're going to solve bigger problems
than the smaller problems what we have
today. Because major smaller problems,
AI is going to take care of it.
The rest of the problems.
We could have a bigger problems to solve.
What we saw 25 years back,
problem we are not solving today as a
product manager.
Problem today we are talking about human
robots introducing in hospitals,
in nurses, in healthcare, in elderly care,
introducing.
These problems was not there 25 years
back. Do you agree?
Today product managers talk about
These problems, early 25 years back,
we were talking about building a mobile
app for restaurants,
building up a sort of ERP,
or SaaS application, website.
These are the problems we were solving 25
years back. Today,
we're not talking about that. Today,
we are talking about building up a
massive e-cars and...
building up, you know,
all these robotics for the healthcare,
laser surgeries,
robotic surgery solutions we are trying
to introduce onto it.
So it's not displacement of humans.
Basically,
we are trying to bring in more efficiency
to the problems what we solve. Humans are.
..
Even though more efficient,
at the same time humans make more
mistakes. We are trying,
the industries are cutting down those
mistakes and trying to introduce,
especially when there is a monotonous
work.
If you ask a human to do repeatedly same
thing for 1000 times out of,
they're going to make a lot of,
even though the export level goes up,
but they
tend to make more mistakes because they
get boredom.
They get bored of this doing the same
thing. Whereas a robots is not,
there's no question of robot.
They keep doing the same thing even 1000
times in a day till the mission goes out.
You know,
there's advantage and disordageous.
Thank you, thank you.
I see maintenance was quite expensive.
Yes.
Maintenance of robots are quite expensive.
Vanishka, Jain, that's a question. Yes,
today. Things are changing.
A lot of suppliers are coming into the
market. Competition is coming up.
People are trying to bring in more
innovation to that,
trying to reduce the price of robots.
So eventually you see price.
going down and you know,
EV cars were electric cars were very
expensive when it got introduced earlier.
Today,
you see electric cars have become more
cheaper and because of more suppliers,
more subsidies,
government started giving in a lot of
things started giving in,
startup people started focusing solar,
solar was very expensive before.
Today,
solar is definitely little expensive.
Still, it is coming at a lower rate,
right? So every trend,
any changes you go through it,
you have to go through that.
I like regentic robots, yes.
We'll cover those AI agents as we move
forward building a AI agentic services.
I have some experience working on that in
a real time in our industry,
probably I'll be sharing.
I'd love to see your thoughts also.
Right.
All right.
I hope this is a lean startup canvas.
How many people have seen this canvas?
This is a very popular canvas which has
been...
Popular in the startup world. You know,
if you're in a startup world,
people lean startup world,
people always see this as a canvas.
They talk about it.
You're seeing this, uh...
Okay, this is a problem.
You basically you're trying to...
There are 9 segment boxes are there and
you're trying to...
your business model,
you're putting into a canvas.
The first more important thing is what
are we trying to solve?
So you try to identify the problem,
what you're trying to solve in your
business. In certain situation,
it is sometimes very difficult to find a
taxi.
The price of a trip is not known in
advance,
and sometimes it is not transparent.
Paying a taxi driver often requires
having more cash.
This was the Uber's problem, correct?
Uber came up with this problem.
And as a solution,
they built up a driver and customer
ecosystem they built.
The fixed fee known when that trip is
booked. Payment process via a credit card.
See the problems each individually.
identified the problem and they gave a
solution to it.
So this is the way any,
this is a business model canvas,
very popular in the lean startup world.
They, not nowadays,
earlier days they used to follow this
kind of thing, identifying the problem.
Who does it? Could be a CEO,
could be a product manager.
Find out what are we trying to solve.
The problem, according to the Uber,
what they understood,
in certain situations,
it is very difficult to find a taxi,
especially in the nights.
The price of a trip is also not known.
Paying a taxi on a cash is not possible.
So they want to solve the problem.
They brought in an ecosystem called Uber,
and they said, okay,
you can find taxis anytime.
Any part of the day?
You can, you can, you know the fee,
how much you're going to pay,
but then before you take a trip,
so you can pay credit card or UPI done.
You understood? This is the way of,
this is a very popular one.
And what is the value proposition you're
giving to the customers?
Offering an individual transport
solutions in any big cities worldwide.
That's the value proposition you're
giving it.
Right, you can build it up in 65,
the unfair advent 3 billion network
driver network available in 65 countries
over 65.
How you want to distribute this app
through mobile app?
Promo codes, the mailing,
you can also do that.
That's a channel of distributions you can
do it.
So this is another way of identifying
your business idea and trying to see
who's your,
what is the problem you have to solve?
What's your solution to the problem?
How do you track whether you are solving
the problem?
How do you measure your success,
whether you have solved the problem or
not? If number of trips...
How do you measure in this case?
Can you can someone say how this measure
the success of Uber in this?
I solved it, Uber gave the solution.
How Uber decided,
let's say it's going through a successful
model, how it knows it.
Exactly, RAKESH, that's a perfect, right?
Number of bookings, reachability, usage,
subscription, yes, return.
Number of bookings,
number of trips going up is the biggest
success metrics watch they measure every
day. Any city they introduce,
they see number of bookings goes every
day.
They keep track of those things on a
day-to-day basis.
When they introduce in India,
Uber came in,
they keep a watch on every day,
are their bookings going up?
The number of users using it is going up.
The average price of a trip is going up.
Average revenue of a driver,
is it going up?
Because the driver is more important for
them.
If the driver's revenue is not going up,
this whole model is not going to be
successful.
So, this is a key metrics they will show.
So there's a problem, there's a solution,
there's a success metrics which they
continuously measure to see the solution
is solving the problem.
And are they making,
is this decision what they've taken,
is it successful or not?
Yeah,
rate of both driver and customer feedback,
yes.
Less the number of cancel bookings.
Perfect. Return of investment. Yes.
So this is a nice way of putting,
in case you have a business idea,
put it in this canvas,
identify what's your problem that you're
solving,
what's the solutions you are trying to
give for this problem,
what is the metrics you're going to
measure to see where your...
Your, your, your, uh,
your succeeded in this problem solving,
whether you have succeeded or not.
And that's very important.
The first three boxes, very, very,
very important. Now,
how do you reach all that is all the
subsequent boxes?
Okay.
Any questions here?
All right.
Hope we got a clarity on what's a product
management. Why a product management?
Let's get on to what is a product
management now.
So what is product management?
So a basic definition is the product
management is a process of identifying
customer problems,
deciding what product to build,
guiding its development,
and continuously improving it to create
value for customers and the business.
Product Management is a process of
identifying customer problems,
deciding what product to build,
guiding its development,
and continually improving.
If you relate this statement to this,
as imagine you are a CEO and you get all
the customer problems,
like add more dishes,
your mobile app is slow,
your food delivery is take time,
introduce loyalty.
You identify the second and third is the
most important priority we need to focus.
And then you're guiding your development
to get that fixed.
That is nothing but a product management
is all about.
Product Management is a process of
identifying customer problems and
deciding what product to build,
guiding its development,
and continuously improving it to create
value for customers and business.
It focuses on answering four important
questions. Who are we building for?
Okay, what should we build?
Why should we build it?
How do we know it is successful?
Who are we building for?
Coming back to this lean diagram, canvas.
Okay,
I'll be coming up or touching this one
frequently.
So who are we building this one for?
Basically,
we are building up for customers who's
taking a trip, who's going for a, yeah,
for the customers, exactly,
for the customer or for the customers
who's going taking a ride on the taxi,
who's looking for taking a ride in the
taxi. They are our customers, all right,
and...
What should we build? We should build a,
according to this,
we should build an ecosystem,
a platform which connects drivers and
customers. Okay,
so the one single platform where both
drivers and customers can connect
together and communicate to each other.
Why should we build it?
Because this can help you to solve.
helping them to place and book a taxi
anytime, pay in cash anytime.
They know what's a trip fare.
Any point of time,
they know exactly what's a fare they
would do pay for it.
So how do you know it is successful?
Number of trips when it goes up,
the number of users usage is going up,
the average trip price is going up,
average revenue for a driver goes up.
So if it all this metrics measure is
going up, is increases,
we know it is successful.
Okay,
that is what a product manager is about.
It focuses on 4 important questions.
Who are we building for?
What should we build it?
Why should we build it?
How do you know it is successful?
All right.
Any other examples you would like to give
or real time examples you anyone want to
share?
Product management is a subset of product
management.
Product development is exactly, yes.
Product management development, yes. Yes,
product development is subset of product
management.
Product Management as such company
engineering we call this today.
Earlier they used to call product
managers a separate team and there'll be
an engineering team.
But today people are merging into one
single where engineering into that
there'll be a product team,
there's a development team,
there's a QA team,
there's a lot of teams comes into it.
Yes, product management,
you can say it's a subset,
but it comes under subset of engineering
actually,
in a software companies nowadays.
Especially a company like Amazon,
all these companies,
they focus on mobile products.
They have more focus on engineering team.
So the divisions goes like this,
engineering.
Sales, and then your marketing,
and the engineering is divided into
product management,
and then comes development, QA.
These are segments goes on to it,
and the product management team goes on
developing,
focusing on requirements and all that,
and they hand over to engineering team,
development team,
the development team completes, builds it.
Product hands over to the QA,
so that's a structure of it.
Okay,
let's see what is the product development
lifecycle.
Is the end of end process of transferring
customer.
a problem or a market opportunity into a
successful product,
continuously improving its base on
customer feedback and customer outcome.
So product development lifecycle is the
end-to-end process of transforming a
customer problem or a market opportunity
into a successful product.
and continuously improving it based on
customer feedback and customer.
So basically the whole development
lifecycle, SDLC,
they call it software development.
Product has its own lifecycle, PDLC.
It's called a product lifecycle
management.
So basically it covers end-to-end process
of transforming a problem,
customer problem.
in or a market opportunity into a
successful product or a continuously
improving service based on customer
feedback and customer outcomes.
That's the SDPDLC process actually is all
about. So starting from when he covers it,
it covers with the...
Customer problem. You do market research.
Let's say you want to build up a humanoid
robots. That's your idea.
Let's assume you are building a startup.
Now you have figured out labor shortage
is a big problem in the restaurant
industry. Whenever you go to restaurants.
You see the delivery takes a long time to
deliver food to the table.
He had a limited of two deliveries,
but 50 tables are there.
You have only two deliveries,
two delivery boys or three delivery boys
are there, waiters are there.
And they are juggling between multiple
tables orders.
The delay is going up more than 15,
20 minutes just to deliver.
The food is ready,
but to deliver from the kitchen to this,
your table, it takes 10 to 15 minutes.
That's a problem you are trying to solve.
Got it.
Let's assume you're building up a robot
humanoid robot to get that problem solved.
Now what you're trying to do is this is a
problem.
The customer problem is the restaurant
owner comes and tells you.
Hey, I, I, whenever I, ohh,
you go to the any restaurants, you notice?
The food to deliver to your table,
it takes nearly 10 to 15 minutes or
sometimes it goes to 30 minutes.
You get irritated, you're hungry,
you're frustrated.
You want to solve this problem.
Any restaurant you go crowded,
you find this problem everywhere.
Now you want to solve this problem.
Your idea clicks.
that you want to,
you have this humanoid robot came into
your mind and said,
can this humanoid robots can solve this
problem?
You're doing some market research.
What is the potential, where do we, what,
how the human robots can handle? You say,
yes, it can solve.
Now you want to see what kind of cost,
where you can procure.
what kind of technology stack is
available to program to that?
How much it going to cost,
end cost is going to be?
My labor waiter cost is in a month, 30,
000, whereas your omen and robbers,
I need to spend 15,00,000 per month,
per year, or 10 to 15,00,000 I need to,
what is my ROI, return of investments?
whether that humanoid robots can solve
this problem.
All this goes into market research.
Okay, now you figure out a viable model.
You got a vendor in China and who said he
can give you in 50% the cost of the
robots at a very reasonable cost.
And now you decide, it strikes you,
you said,
why not build a Roman and Robert?
We'll bring up all the parts from China
and assemble over here.
Build a home humanoid robots and try to
give a trial run to some restaurant.
And, and program in such a way,
integrate to their POS system,
point of sale system, and kitchen system,
and try to do a trial run,
see whether this is a successful or not,
whether it can solve the problem.
Then idea came in and you built up,
you identified the business, how it go,
where to procure the robot parts,
where do we assemble it,
what kind of programming has to go on,
what kind of integrations it has to go on,
everything you have done that you have
put up into a document.
That concept is called idea generation.
Then you prioritize it. Okay,
now you know, okay, as a trial run,
they call it the MVP,
minimum viable product.
So in a viable product,
what it does is you bring in one,
two robots,
you're not going to procure hundreds of
robots,
you're not ready to launch the market
still, you're...
You're going to give a try.
And you prioritize it and see one or two
robots you bring in,
you procure from the vendor.
Now you accordingly,
you program that integrating with other
things and make it work for a small
restaurant. And you develop it, test it,
and release it,
and give it to the restaurant to test it.
and wait for the customer's feedback.
And every day you monitor,
you see whether it serves a purpose,
whether the response time of robots has
increased, what's the delivery time,
whether earlier the same restaurant,
you go and talk to the restaurant,
say to the owner and say, hey,
I know you are having a challenge in
having one more.
a waiter or getting a reliable waiter,
why not take this robot and give a try?
And he's happy and he's ready to do that.
And you test run in that same restaurant
where you go every day and you take a
feedback and you improve,
see the number of time what from the
kitchen to the table is reduced from 30
minutes today to 15 minutes or 10 minutes.
The customer is happy.
The owner is happy.
The customers and the who is coming and
taking orders, taking,
they are pretty happy.
The food is coming in time.
Now,
you ought to see the measure number of
delivery or from kitchen to how many
orders are delivered.
What's the time it was ordered?
What is the time it got delivered?
How many errors it created?
It would have gone robot instead of going
to 12 table number 12,
it would have gone to 12 number.
13 or it would have gone to 12 table
number 15 instead of 12. These are errors.
How much errors it has reduced?
Could be starting with be 90% errors.
Every time it goes and gives a wrong
table,
takes a wrong dishes to wrong table. Now,
as you train, keep training, training,
training, you finally arrive.
to accuracy of 99%,
where you are able to identify the right
table and deliver the food within time
without lesser. Now,
not zero errors could be errors,
but that's a way of measuring success.
And finally, improving, improving,
improving, improving till you get it.
So you identify a problem.
And finally you gave a solution.
You saw how you did you do you notice how
the whole process works?
I've just given an example of a humanoid
robots where if it deployed to a
restaurant and this is how we do it today.
If a startup company does it,
that's a way you go identify a problem,
you do a research, you do ideation,
you prioritize the features which you
want to develop and design your solutions
to it. You develop solutions.
You test it, you release it,
and you take a feedback from there.
You measure the success of the feedback,
then you improve it on a continuous basis.
On this continuous basis, measure success,
I told you.
Even you release a human robot,
he attacks,
it expects you to deliver 100%.
Right dishes has to go to the right table.
Out of 95%, it goes 5%,
it goes to the wrong table.
Something wrong in the logic.
So you keep improving the algorithm and
vision sensor or whatever the logic you
built in to identify the table and the
positions, all that,
and tries to improve it.
So that as you see it within two months,
you see improvement in terms of accuracy
level.
So that is the whole product development
life cycle.
I give an example of humanoid robot,
but you can use the same structure,
life cycle structure,
any product you develop,
whether it a food delivery app like
Swiggy or...
Zomato or could be any kind of app or
delivery app which you do it,
you go through the same development
lifecycle. Do you agree?
Any other thoughts, ideas?
Any other ideas or thoughts you guys have?
Is anyone developing AI agentic apps in
your day-to-day work today?
Oh great, RAKESH and Basu. Yeah,
what kind of domain is it on pharmacy,
healthcare,
or what domain do you focus on right now?
Just started with the team, ANKUR. Okay,
great. So, all right, great.
That's fit tech. Okay. All right.
What kind of technology is that? I mean,
what are we working on? Healthcare? Okay,
great. Super. FinTech is the one thing.
All right. Logistic. That's amazing.
I've worked for logistic ANKUR for more
than 10 years. I've worked on logistic.
Basically,
what we develop is we have oil and gas.
I told you oil and gas, we deliver oil.
We build a software solutions for
or oil delivery, wholesalers and retail,
they go and deliver oil to us.
So basically we will forecast their route,
which route they have to take to go in
time and deliver.
And they see the weather reports and all
that peak predict and say,
this is the route you need to take,
especially for the North America. Yeah.
So that's a.
That's amazing.
I see very interesting to hear that
people are working on AI agentic apps,
especially for FinTech and healthcare.
We have built a dashboard for tax
fraction for foreign countries and
clients. Wow.
We write tax caption foreign countries
and clients, so basically what it does,
uh...
Probably I'll just say...
I see an interesting.
Okay.
Internal banking application fit risk. OK,
that's amazing.
Internal banking application fit risk,
okay.
Okay, interesting, interesting.
So AI agent tech is a talk of the town
today. People all,
most of the companies are trying to use
AI in different forms in the applications.
We use AI,
we are more of hospitality industries.
So what do you mean hospital?
We build application for ranches.
So basically what it does is when a guest
comes in, we know exactly,
let's say we have a one example we are
trying to solve is.
We know, like, basically,
like we are trying to connect those IoTs
and rooms IoT, where, yeah,
usage of AI is limited development so far.
GitHub Copilot and Cloud models and Cloud
Code. Great. OK, alright,
it's very expensive.
GitHub Copilot with Cloud models and
Cloud.
It all looks very interesting,
but very expensive. You have to shell out,
they have limitations of usage every day.
So you have to,
it's a huge investment company has to
make it to leverage AI models today,
right? Even though it looks, yeah,
urban infrastructure planning,
that's amazing. Yeah, with a low delivery.
for urban infrastructure planning.
Interesting.
O K.
We'll talk about more of agentic AI and
all that as we move forward.
Thank you for your feedback. Amazing.
Nice crowd.
I'm so happy to be to learn more about
your projects on a day-to-day.
I'm looking forward to that as well.
Yes, it's too expensive.
Our company plan to stop using it.
This is exactly,
this is the same problem we all have,
go through it. We all, companies initiate,
they got excited to give it early days,
then slowly they stopped it.
They restricted.
So this is a common trend we are seeing
in all the companies.
This is what we are seeing it.
Okay, great. Salesforce.
Yeah,
token maximum token is a biggest talk of
the town now in the office,
whether we using the efficiently using
the token is more important now.
Right, the most scared, you know,
scarcity today is a token, right?
How best to use a token is more important,
not the AI or tool,
how best to utilize a token and prompt
has to be so efficient in such a way that
you minimize the token usage.
So that is the biggest art of using of AI
models, I guess, nowadays.
All right.
Interesting. So what is step one? Okay,
let's go one by one. Okay,
this is a very important lifecycle.
We need this is what we're going to cover
one by one.
And we go in detail about the techniques
and other frameworks available one by one
later on.
But today we're just touching upon the
one by one about.
What are we trying to focus on this?
So the step one is identifying customer
problem.
In the whole development lifecycle,
step one is that.
So everything starts with a problem.
We all know it, not a feature.
It's a problem.
What are we trying to solve? Right?
Question to ask,
what problems are customer facing?
Often does it occur?
How severe is a problem?
Is it worth solving? Very good question.
So today,
coming relate to my example of humanoid
robots in restaurants.
I'm just thinking what problems are
customer facing today?
Hotel owners are not able to hire waiters,
experienced waiters.
Or the waiters churn,
they keep leaving the hotel within two
days. They don't stay long.
The salaries have gone up.
They have a lot of,
they take a lot of leaves, so...
Hiring a waiter in a restaurant is
becoming a biggest challenge the
customers of having,
hotel owners are having today.
They hire people from different regions,
they don't stay for long.
That's a cost. You know,
you imagine no waiters are ready to come
for 10,000 and all. Nowadays,
waiters are going up to 20, 25,000.
Imagine we have 4 waiters or lakh,
you pay for it. Your cost,
where it ends up on there again to the
customers who are coming and eating there.
What problem is it? This is a waiting.
So what happens? Your services,
since your waiter's availability is not
there, your service has gone down, poor.
So often does it occur?
There's a problem wherever you go,
whichever restaurants you go,
they go through the same challenge.
They have the waiters,
hiring a waiter is the biggest challenge
every restaurants have is today.
Labor issues, shortage,
both in hotels and restaurants have the
serious shortage today.
How severe is the problem?
It is impacting the customer satisfaction
when a per customer food is good,
but if it doesn't serve the food in hot
within the time,
the customers are not going to be happy
with that your restaurant, so...
It is a severe problem for hotel owners.
Is it worth solving?
It's not one restaurant in the city.
There are a lot of restaurants are going
through the same challenge.
So today it may be a very expensive
solution for a restaurant.
But as we move on,
when more number of suppliers comes into
it,
the cost of the robots is going to
definitely go down.
You're going to procure in China,
you may procure from India.
You may have suppliers in India.
You will build up your own solutions.
You may have ready-made,
they call it robotic,
human robotic framework available,
open source frameworks available.
You may have frameworks and you may have
ready-made skills,
which is already you can download through
AI Agent.
cloud agent called skills they called us.
You know what is skills, right?
We're talking about skills in cloud
skills.
Hope you all know what I'm talking about
skills.
So you may have human robotic ready-made
skills which you could download and
configure within one day, two day,
which used to take months now,
which used to come.
So it is worth solving.
If the problem is huge and more number of
customers are going, the market is big.
They call it a TAM,
Total Addressable Market. Okay,
this is a keyword you need to understand,
TAM. TAM is nothing but.
How big is a market size? 100 million,
200 million size of problems you're
trying to solve. And if it is,
then it's worth going,
addressing that problem, solving.
If you have only one,
two restaurants are asking for this and
you don't want to invest 15,00,000,
and their one,
two customers will be interested to pay
15,00,000 to buy the robots.
But other medium-sized restaurants there,
they find it very expensive and they may
not go for it.
So.
Is it worth it to invest your money and
time to build a robot just to two or
three restaurants who's ready to pay for
it?
Or are you ready to wait for and see how
it is,
where the parts goes down and then try to
develop? So a lot of, you're trying to,
as a product manager,
you need to spend your time and research.
Or can you procure products where instead
of 15,00,000 paying,
can we reduce that to 5,00,000?
Is that a benchmark cost we can set?
So that we can do research from the
owners and say how much value,
how much price they are ready to pay for
women and robots. 15,00,000 is expensive.
What is the best price ticket? They say,
I don't mind, they don't mind paying 5,00,
000. Okay, 5,00,000 per robot. The ROI,
they can take it in 5, 6,
one month because you're paying to a
weighted 20,000.
So even if the robots use it for three
years, four years,
the ROA is more profitable. And again,
profitable in terms of service, speed,
delivery, all that, if you see it,
the ROA is much higher than the human
waiters.
So identifying the customer problem is
very important. It starts with a problem,
not with a feature.
What problem our customers are facing?
How often does it occur?
How severe is a problem?
Is it worth solving the problem?
K.
TAM is really not easy to predict. Yes,
TAM is not relatively easy to predict
because you go with a gut estimate here,
YADAV. Basically what you do,
you go with the number of restaurants in
whole India. Okay,
let's say I'm going to focus TAM
restaurants only in India,
urban restaurants. So I go with...
identifying the restaurants,
total number of restaurants,
maybe 5000 restaurants are there in
Bangalore, Hyderabad, in Chennai.
And then I see, okay, out of that 5000,
how many restaurants have premium
restaurants?
Who's ready to invest on Urban?
Though I'll go with 5000,
I'll cut down to 3000 to 2000.
or it could be 1000. Out of 1000,
how many people would be interested?
They call it a service addressable market.
There's a call SAM. It's called service.
Out of time,
all will not be able to be interested to
your solution. Out of that,
only about 500 restaurants would be
interested to buy you.
They call it a service addressable market.
Only for them you will be able to,
you can sell your solution to that.
Rest all is just a market,
but it is not useful for you.
So, that's a very good feedback. Yeah,
the TAM is really not easy to predict,
but a lot of research goes into it.
You know, you need to work with,
you need to work with a lot of research
teams to identify what's the actual TAM
with a public data which is available,
and then you based on correlate all that.
build up and then you come up with a time,
then identify out of the time of 5000
restaurants,
rupee product burning money suddenly
becomes time becomes okay,
selling a selling a 10 rupee product at
90,
burning money suddenly time becomes big.
What is the difference between?
Okay, total addressable.
I'm just giving it.
Total addressable market and service
addressable market. If you want it,
very good from RAJ, you see of them. Okay.
See, total addressable market I give you,
that's a very good, I like.
There's a question between Sarkar,
Anupam Sarkar,
what is TAM and what is TAM? Anupam,
this is a, let's say an example,
I give an example.
I want to build a human and drop it,
but I want to understand, I want to know.
through which restaurants I can sell,
how big is the market for me?
For that I need to do some research and
find out. Okay, I have in my India,
out of the urban cities,
if I put together all the urban
restaurants, fine dining restaurants,
have some 10,000 restaurants.
Total number of restaurants from a public
data, that's called 10,000 restaurants.
That is total addressable market.
I can get all 10,000 as my customer. No,
that's not possible, right? So out of 10,
000,
I try to break down into urban premium
restaurants who can have higher budget.
who can ready to invest on this kind of
robots or lower restaurants, you know,
small, small restaurants.
That is not my addressable,
immediate addressable market.
So that is not serviceable immediately
for me. I can't target those restaurants.
So out of 10,000 total addressable market,
I need to identify which are restaurants
I can address,
who's going to be my ideal market.
Customers.
I have to identify in that out of 10,000,
only 1000 customers who is into the fine
dining restaurants, premium restaurants,
high value customers who are ready to
invest on it. So the 1000 is called SAM,
SAM, the Service Addressable Market.
And the 10,
000 is called total out of the total
addressable market, 10,000.
My service addressable market is only
1000. So my, even though I have 10,000,
I can't go to those 10,000.
I can't go and value my business and say
I can reach 10,000. No, because my,
those are just a smaller restaurants
which are not ready.
My service and driven market is where I
need to prioritize. I need to focus.
That is going to be my market where I
need to focus on.
Did I explain you clearly or do you want
more examples of that, Radha?
Thank you. Okay.
Right,
so this is very important for a any
startups when you do it.
You need to identify what's your TAM and
what's your SAM.
Any market you go on to it,
let's say you have become more in this in
India,
become very popular and you have a market
of share of you started,
you are the innovator, you got it,
you got some under restaurants are using
robots.
Now you are slowly going on to Singapore.
Now you have to identify what is a TAM
and what is SAM.
identify total number of restaurants in
Singapore,
and how many restaurants come into your
category of customers,
and they called us SAM,
Serviceable Addressable Market.
Out of 1000 in Singapore, 100 service,
then you only focus on that's your market
size, and you first address that.
So that is.
Very important when you go to any new
market and you try to target your market
to sell your product.
Just give me a minute, please.
Okay, no, you then the market,
you identify the customer,
then you go for market research.
Once a problem is identified,
you validate that it is real worth
solving. Activities,
you do customer interviews,
you do surveys,
you do competitor analysis,
you usage analytics,
you do support ticket analysis.
You took multiple way to take a to study
the market and see whether it's worth
solving. Again,
coming back to humanoid robots for
restaurants,
that's my that's going to be my easier
example,
which I'm going to share all my problems,
so that let's stick to one problem.
So now I have the humanoid robots. Now I..
.
I want to sell it to all the restaurants.
Now,
how do we identify whether it has a
potential,
whether customers are going to buy it,
whether they are having the same problem?
So I do, I go to all the restaurants,
do walk-ins, column up, do a,
go to most of the restaurants and talk to
the owner and find out.
GM and owners are identified,
do some interviews, do some surveys.
and see any other competitors are there
in that segment.
Do analysis and see how many people,
who's a market leader in that segment.
In humanoid robots, who's leading,
what's the revenue they're making,
what's the profitability they're making,
how many customers they have,
and what is the addressable market they
focus on, which market they focus on.
Where is a gap there?
Where is their weakness? SWAT analysis,
let's do a SWAT analysis on their
competitor,
finding out what their strengths and
weaknesses,
threats and opportunity they have.
Where do we go? Where we can become more,
you know,
where we have an edge against that
competitor.
So there is again a competent analysis
you can do it.
Then you try to show usage analytics.
In case you are already there,
you can try using analytics.
If it is a new launch idea,
the last two will not be applicable.
Usage analytics and supporting analytics.
Those are a product which is already in
the market. Now using,
then you try to use the people usage
metrics, daily active users,
how many people are using that thing,
all that you capture,
then you try to identify your adaption
rate of your product.
in the market?
Is it going up or going down? Clear?
So...
Once a problem is identified,
validate that it is worth real and worth
solving. Activities, customer interviews,
surveys, competent analysis,
usage analytics, support ticket analysis.
Any questions here?
So the problem is,
was the issue with human waiters being
difficult to manage. Yes. Yes,
the human cost of human waiters are going
up. That's one problem. Second,
availability of human waiters
is going down.
We are not getting the labor shortage is
there.
People are not ready to take up the job
of labor. They're going to,
they love to go and do swiggy delivery
instead of being a human waiter.
You got it? And expensive availability,
they take a lot of leaves,
all that comes as a.
Problem.
In that case,
the market should focus on whether it is,
yes,
whether it is difficult to manage the
human weighters.
It's a real problem rather than finding
whether the robots are solution.
Is that right? Yes, that's a real problem.
Are they having all,
whether all the restaurants having the
real,
is that the problem they all having it?
A labor shortage, waiter shortage,
are they having the real problem?
First thing is, that's a problem.
And again, on the same time, you have to,
because customers will not know, right?
No customers, nowadays, any customers,
you walk in restaurants,
they won't know human robots can help
them also because they're not experienced
it. They're slowly hearing that,
but they're not experienced it.
If you ask them,
human robots can solve their problem,
they don't know. They say, no idea.
That's the answer,
you will get it from the owners. So this,
you need to educate them.
It takes time to educate them and try to
deploy some robots and extreme trial run,
see how it goes, all that,
you have to do it. Until then,
he won't be convinced.
But he has a problem.
The waiter shortage is a big problem.
He's going through it. How do we solve?
That's a question he is coming up with.
Yes,
each in few days we might have a human.
Chefs is just personal for I think
there's a restaurant in New York or
somewhere they saw automatically a
robotics pizzas, pizzas,
especially pizzas are made by human
robotics, right? They're based on the,
yeah, sky robot chefs. Got it. Yeah,
I think it's.
you saw in the robotics in YouTube is
there. So that's,
it's going to happen soon.
It's just a time, you know,
anytime it can, anyone, a few restaurants,
they adopt slowly,
everyone will start adopting it. Again,
in India, labour's a little more higher,
availability of getting labour's high,
so people still adopt.
They prefer to have labors.
Since once when you have a shortage
coming in,
you may find this becoming a difficulty
in future. I see that.
Okay.
All right, generate ideas. All right,
new identified human shortage is a
problem. Wait is a problem. We identified.
We did some research.
Every owners have 95% of the restaurants
out of 100 customers.
You went and saw 90 complain the same
problem.
Now you saw that's a big problem to solve.
Okay, now what do we do? Generate ideas.
Brainstorm multiple solutions before
choosing one. One screen check-in,
QR check-in. This is all,
I'm just saying robotics,
I didn't assist this.
Possible solution for a one minute.
I can say, give me a minute.
This is a wrong example.
Okay, see,
I think that's what I think I've covered
everything.
I just want to make sure this is what I
covered. Yeah, what you can do is...
I don't have a robotics.
What are the possible solutions I can
improve it? The restaurants,
I can build up a table level QR code
where you just,
you can do one screen check in.
When you go, you can,
I insert a waiter concept,
I can make it a self-service restaurant
where I introduce a chaos mission.
in the entrance of the restaurants where
you go, key in your request,
what you want,
and go to the counter and take your food
and come and sit and have it.
That's one way of solving the problem,
right?
Most of the labor issues are solved by
that.
They just have a kitchen,
they have a counter, a billing counter.
You just take,
you go on kiosk or even the billing
counter, you can bypass,
you can have a kiosk.
Kiosk machines are there where you feed
your requirement and you get your order
placed and they'll call you on the queue
counter and they just go and deliver.
That's one way of solving.
You can mobile check-ins,
you can do through while coming itself,
while coming into the restaurants,
you can check in,
you can order through mobile and you can
basically,
you come pick up the order and go.
You can reduce the waiting time there.
Many solutions to one problem.
Robotics is 1 problem actually.
Human right robots is 1 problem what
you're trying to solve. This is an idea.
So you need to figure out which is a
possible different solutions available,
where which is feasible budget wise,
time wise,
everything you identify which solution
can be app for restaurants.
at this point of time where they have a,
because restaurants also works on the low
margin business.
They are not a high margin business.
They have a,
even though it looks very high,
but they have a severe shortage of
business because of the competition they
have, all that. So.
is a very high cost expensive.
CapEx is very expensive for restaurant
business.
So they want to keep their costs as low
as possible on the technology side,
even though they love to be trying to try
new things,
but they're very cautious investing on
things.
So that is one thing they have to be very,
you know, gamify the service to customer.
Yeah, that's a very good self-service.
Self-service is a good one.
Cannot be automated by robot and timeless
experience. Yeah,
sushi restaurants have a conveyor belts
which can be programmed for table
delivery. Yes,
that is one thing they do it in Japan.
True customer service cannot be automated
by robot. Yes, I agree.
But imagine, YADAV,
you order a food and you,
the human waiter waiting for 30 minutes,
even come and deliver.
What is the point in delivering after 30
minutes delay with a smile?
You get irritated, you hungry,
you got exhausted, right? Right.
I think for me, I can.
Better give me a.
Bookworms will be out of time. Yeah.
Ten minutes if you deliver, even with a,
I'm okay.
When robots comes and delivers in 10
minutes or 5 minutes after delivery,
hot food, I'm okay.
I don't want the smiling waiter who takes
30 minutes to deliver.
Got it.
Yeah, I agree.
We took a we can we do an app called
Smart Queue for weight a problem.
Queue menus pane app, QR generated,
self checkout. Yep.
Do you have an app, DHRUV?
You developed it or how it works?
Is it a smart queue? Oh, not me,
it's an app. It's on App Store. Okay,
I see that. I got it. Okay,
we developed this kind of apps in our
industry for a business. We have this.
I was just thinking that whether you have
developed it. Thank you, Dhruv. Yeah,
we have this kind of smart apps where we
deliver to our customers,
where from a room they can place an order.
is used for many industries and companies
on the smart queue. Yes,
that's a very good one.
That's exactly another way of solving
problem, right? They don't have labor.
You do a menu, pay an app,
queue are generated, self-checkout of it,
and you go and take it out.
A lot of restaurants are now using app
based menu, order payments, extra,
wait is on loop only.
to bring food to tables.
Even the waiters are trying to solve,
they don't want these waiters to get out
of the loop because they're very,
sometimes some restaurants are,
they're expensive also.
Operate, yeah, yep.
All right, now we know all this,
identified market research,
we did some ideas,
we decided let's go with this.
Not every idea should be built.
Now prioritize based on customer value,
business impact, technical effort, cost,
you know, TAM.
Timing.
It's a timing, actually.
Okay, customer value, business impact,
technical effort, cost, timing.
So you have a product and now you got an
idea out of all those ideas.
Now I have one screen check in,
QR code check in, facial recognitions,
mobile self check ins,
all the solutions you have come up with.
Now I have to go prioritize based on
these segments.
Customer value,
which can give a better customer value.
which can give a business best of
business and more business impact in
terms of revenue,
in terms of satisfaction for the customer.
Effort to develop and deliver.
Women robots is not going to be easy
solution for me.
It may take me a year to deliver one
robot and get to the solution. Today,
as on today,
you may find it within a few months,
but I'm saying.
And then cost of it. My robots cost me 6,
00,000 to 7,00,000,
whereas the QR code I can deliver,
it's going to be 10,00,
000 human robots more than that.
I'm just giving an idea.
Human robots is going to cost be very
expensive, actually, if you see it.
How much is it?
You know what,
the entry level for budget and education
for lighter weight watts,
it comes to roughly about 13,000.
It's a very expensive only, restaurants.
Food serving robot has cost you 1,40,000.
I'm just giving a small.
You see this food serving robot.
It's costable 1 lakh in India mart.
They're selling this. Basically,
they're selling for hospitals,
food and 40 kmg.
The innovative futuristic solution
designed to automate food serving in
restaurants and food in large scale.
This robot enhances efficiency,
labour dependency,
ensures hygienic food of flavour to
consume consumers too.
It's not bad, you know,
the price has really gone down.
It's come down to 1,48. It was like,
the labors are, we are paying 20,
000 rupees. See the ROI,
even if this works out, out of 10 labors,
if you have two thing, 30,000 per month,
1.5,
you can recover the cost in 10 months and
you will be able to be profitable with
the robots.
Right.
Just give me a minute.
Let's take a break for one minute.
Please get some water. Don't mind. One,
2 minutes.
Is that okay?
All right, we'll be back. Thank you. Yeah,
I see that response from Nishka,
the robots are still expensive. Yes,
it is expensive. Today, everything,
if you go for a AI generative app,
cloud codes are very expensive, right?
The token price has gone up.
Imagine five years back or three years
back when Cloud OpenAI introduced Codex,
or it was very expensive. Today, Sonet,
Opus, or Cloud,
when you compare to Gemini,
when you compare to other things coming
up.
you see the competition coming up,
the token price is coming down slowly,
it's going to reduce and it will
eventually if you see this,
it's going to come down.
Today it is expensive.
It is very expensive to use this all.
But eventually if you see this,
when the demand goes up,
a lot of suppliers comes in.
they'll try to reduce the prices.
That's the process of innovation.
You have to,
who goes in the earlier stage in their
adopting the earlier technologies,
they have to pay a little extra cost to
try things faster than the person who
takes it to the last.
So it depends on where, which part of the.
adoption cycle you go in. So yes, I agree,
Nishka.
So again, when you go for a,
I'm coming back to creating user
experiences. When you come up with that,
basically what you do, you identified,
okay, now I want to build up a QR code.
I'll go with this human robot is one
thing. And see, the problem is,
what is the problem are we trying to
solve in this case is?
The restaurant is not a human waiter
alone.
The actual problem is the customers
waiting time to get their food.
That is the biggest problem they're
having. They ordered,
it is taking 30 minutes,
45 minutes to deliver. Why?
It could be one,
the food is not ready in the kitchen.
to the waiters because we have shortage
of waiters where because waiters are
taking time to deliver to the table.
Could be third as more number of
customers are there in the restaurant at
the same time, wrong timing, we are gone.
Could be various reason.
So how do we reduce the wait time?
That is the one thing we are trying to
solve. You know, as a, let's say, as what,
through a shed that's called smart queue.
Imagine you.
wait for the waiter to come from the
place to deliver to your table.
You want to wait 30, 45 minutes,
he has to deliver.
Instead of you just take a,
best solution is QR code in the table
which are placed in all the tables.
You just scan your code, QR,
and just place your,
browse through your menu, place an order.
Pay the payment.
When order ready,
it notifies in your mobile,
and you go to the counter, pick the food,
and come to your table and have it.
In this case, everything is simplified,
right? Your payment is simplified,
you're placing order simplified,
your payment is simplified,
and you know there's no dependency of any
person in between placing an order till
you pay.
pay your cash.
And even you go and deliver,
you pick it from the counter and just
come back to your table and have it.
You see all the frictions have been
reduced here.
So this is a problem you're trying to do
it.
You are solving this.
Okay,
now prioritize features is basically now
identified. I have okay with this example,
human robot is good for me,
but very expensive for me today because I
have to assemble,
I have to bring in from China or other
parts, all those,
it's still the logistic is very quite
expensive for me.
And I don't see today the market is not
ready to go for.
robots,
humanoid robot at a very mass scale.
Only a few restaurants are ready. I mean,
I'm not ready to invest all my time on.
catering the smaller segment of SAM.
I want to go for a bigger market.
So I built up a QR code process where,
like I walked through shared a smart
queue where I built up a QR code.
Restaurants can upload their menu.
And I just work with the restaurants and
I'll give a QR code solution to them.
where I'll help them to place the QR code
in all the tables.
And when the customer comes in to the
table, they can scan it.
And I just allow them to place an order.
And the payment is also taken care.
They through pay through UPI or pay
through whatever the app they have it,
and they just pay.
If they have a waiter,
they can come and deliver; otherwise,
they have a search again,
though payment order taking to the cash
payment is all automated,
only though bringing the food to the
table is where.
I have to decide whether I can go with
the order. I can go,
restaurants can give it as a self-check,
self-service model,
or they want to be delivered to the table
order.
It depending upon model the restaurant
wants to go,
I can they can choose to go with.
So, why? OK, now I decided to go with the.
..
By putting the grill at the table,
cutting wait times,
turning birthdays into highway, sorry,
BBQ. Oh, BBQ is amazing, guys.
They put something to act on the table to
keep it and they just stuff you with,
you know,
starters and by the time you'll get
distracted and they know exactly your
starters, you'll fill your stomach.
By the time you come to the main course,
you're done.
So they are very smart in trying to
strategize their food accordingly,
actually. And...
Yeah, for designing of solutions,
the design team creates a user experience.
Then what do you do? Okay, now identified,
I want to go over the QR code solutions,
how to solve this problem with a QR code
placing orders in the table.
So I design a solution,
I build up a wire frames, mock up screens,
user flows, prototypes.
And I go with this deliverable.
As a product manager,
I focus on building up wireframes,
mockups, user flows. Let's go. See,
I'm going to go through this all.
in the following classes one by one in
detail,
but I'm just touching upon this all.
On a step 5, you call it,
this is a deliverables.
When you have this,
then you hand over this,
all your deliverables to the engineering
team, development team.
Then the engineering team builds a
solution. Typical activity,
they go through a sprint planning,
they follow agile process, they do code,
they code review,
they do API integration if it's required
for payment gateway where you need to
integrate your code.
QR code application with the Razor Pay or
Stripe or CC Avenue or PayU or PayTM,
whatever the payment gateway the
restaurant wants to get connected to it,
they can do it.
And all the database changes number,
the product may ensure the team
understands why the features matter.
The product team managers.
The product managers will be involved on
a day-to-day basis with the engineering
team to make sure the features are
developed as per his vision,
what he wants it to be developed.
And he keeps watch of it,
he keeps track of it, all the thing.
And engineer teams,
this is a way of doing it.
One second, though.
Testing,
verify the product works as intended.
Types of testing, functional testing,
integration testing. And then you go,
the development team completes and they
hand over to testing and verify the
product works as intended. That is,
types of testing they run through the
testing, integration, performance testing,
security testing, user acceptance testing.
Then finally, release to customers.
And the production deployment,
release notes, user documentation,
customer communication, team training,
everything is given to the customers as
part of the release.
And.
Okay.
Collect, what do you do?
You collect the customer feedback again,
learning starts from release after
release,
gather feedback from customer surveys,
support tickets, product reviews,
sales team, analytics, you do it.
Customers appreciate the speed,
but request faster guest search.
So they try all that, you know,
customer feedback is very important.
They usually take a survey faster,
tickets on the reviews, it all that.
Then you try to measure the success.
These are the common product metrics they
measure. They go through CSAT.
CSAT is a customer certificate,
satisfaction rating.
And net promoter score is basically
loyalty.
part of it. We'll go one by one.
Monthly active users going up,
feature adoption,
revenue growth is increased, churn rate,
time saved. So basically,
One second, though.
So basically what you do,
customer success onto it and you measure
the success, you go for CSAT.
Thing you try to measure all out of.
Whether they're happy rating or they give
a rating out of five.
Are they happy with that? One to five,
yes.
Net promoter score NPS is another thing
you take it from a customer.
Basically what you do?
You see how likely you recommend a
product to your other friends and family
out of 1 to 10. That is.
NPN promoter score, they go with that.
And whether your monthly active users is
going up or down, how many people,
whether your revenue is going up.
So this is all metrics you try to
correlate and measure it and you try to
identify this. Any questions here?
Very question. Okay,
that's a net promoter score. Yes. See,
basically, net promoter score is,
there's a promoter, detractors,
there are NPS scores are there.
You have out of,
say I'm giving out of 100 people,
you send this.
How many people in out of 1 to 10 are
ready to recommend your product to other
friends and family?
If more if a promoters score is more than
9 and above, your NPS score is good.
If out of 1 to 10,
only five people are ready to recommend
the all rest, all 95 says they're not,
they are five or six,
they give you a score.
Your NPS score is below the average and
your people are not ready to recommend to
other customers.
So there is a formula we'll see on the
next class.
I'll go in detail on the metrics.
Like reference, yeah,
exactly like reference.
Yeah, through I have a quick,
I'll come back to it.
I think I have a product manager's job as
product owners are nothing but.
The next level of product manager,
because product manager cannot do all the
user stories,
building up documentations and all that,
product managers.
So they hand over to the product owner.
Basically,
the second level of product managers are
product owners. Product managers,
basically they do reviews.
They are the one who sets a vision for
the product.
They are the one who prioritize what
product features to go on to the next
release.
Product owners assist product managers in
terms of building up user stories,
building up scenarios, all that.
But the product owners cannot take sets
of vision or set prioritize.
It's always product manager decides for
the product.
So under a product manager,
there will be a two or three product
owners.
They work together as a team and deliver.
Because the product team is big,
everything cannot be done by a product
manager. It has to be.
So the second level team is called
product owners. Each module,
let's say if you have a restaurant app,
or it could be any other app,
let's say if you are under banking
applications,
Remittance will be a one module.
There'll be a, what do you call it,
investments will be another module.
Clearance will be some,
clearance foreign exchange will be a
module.
So each module will have a specialized
product bonus.
They all report to product managers who
takes care of the whole banking
application. So.
Each model they specialize and they'll
but end of the final call will be done by
taken by the product managers.
Am I clear?
Three.
See,
let's say if you go for a food delivery
app and see the problem,
deliveries are delayed during peak hours.
The search,
customers want accurate delivery time.
Idea, AI-based delivery time prediction.
Okay, you could predict.
Based on the traffic of the today's
traffic, if it is on the Monday,
if it is Sunday, traffic in the kitchen,
the use the kitchens or number of orders,
Rd. traffic, weather conditions,
you can predict and say to the customer
that your food is going to be delivered
in 45 minutes or one hour or two.
20 minutes or 10 minutes because
everything is factored, right?
It's not only the kitchen's speed,
efficiency.
You have to make sure the weather
condition is so good,
the rider comes and picks up your food
and delivered in time.
Second is your traffic in the road.
If it is less,
the chances of delivering your food in
time.
So the AI based delivery time prediction
will be a great help in this case.
You agree?
So,
what is the prioritize high business
value, moderate effort, design,
real-time delivery tracker?
develop and build a prediction engine,
tracking UI, simulate peak hour traffic.
You know, this whole thing released,
launched with selected cities,
customer report, improved trust.
Now they see a good trust because during
the peak hour,
the delivery is always delayed and you
commit,
the Zomato commits 30 minutes to deliver
and you deliver after one hour.
they lose trust.
So instead of app predicting,
if it's AI-based prediction with
considering all the AI traffic,
kitchen orders, traffic,
the volume in the business today on that
traffic in the kitchen,
if you consider all this,
if you can predict,
it'll have an accuracy. And you see the...
measure is the delivery compliance has
gone down by 35%. It's a success.
And that's a way you try to solve a
problem.
Any questions?
I think we have solid to cover,
but I don't want to take,
I've only for 20% I've covered.
Probably I'll come on to other things on
the next. I'll just finish this one, okay?
If you see key roles across the lifecycle,
if you see product manager,
they are the one who defined the vision.
prioritize features, measure outcomes.
UI designers,
they're the one who built the wireframes,
mockups,
they work closely with the product
manager, come up with the vision,
documents, deliverables,
then finally hand it over to the
engineering team, then the QA team.
They hand over to a QA team.
And then the ops team has handed over
customer success, customer.
DevOps monitors and deploys and monitors
releases,
collects customer feedback and supports
adoption, sales and marketing, launches,
positions.
This is a role of a team members,
what they do on the prime responsibility
in a product company.
So key takeaways,
start with a customer problem,
not with a solution.
Validate ideas with research before
investing in development.
Prioritize features that deliver highest
value.
Measure outcomes, not just outputs.
Shipping features, not a finish line.
Just because you deliver something,
it is not a finish line.
Is it really adding value to the customer?
What's the impact it gives you to your
business?
Product development is a continuous cycle
of learning, building, measuring,
improving, right? It's not a one-time job.
It's a continuous cycle.
If you want to make your product to the
best of the market.
Here.
This is a key takeaways of today's
session. Do you have any questions?
Hope you got a clarity on it.
Service.
What do you mean, service?
Shisha.
Okay, great.
I'll cover this on the handouts.
Here's a handout where they've asked for
it. I think if you go to it,
you'll have certain books which are
shared.
Okay, I can share this.
I think if you go to the textbooks,
you have inspired, Lean Startup by Eric,
Lean Product by Playbook,
How to Innovate Problems.
These are the three books are there.
And these are popular books.
And the reference books print,
Four Steps of If Any by Steve Blank,
Building Products for Enterprise by
Benjamin, Product Leadership by Richard,
Crossing.
The very good books,
amazing books to read actually for a
product company.
Okay.
So quiz is all there.
I need to work on and see their external
components are there, lab work,
product work, and we need,
I'll work on with this and I'll let you
know what's a quiz and all that.
So you have a quiz, lab,
product available there. Quiz one,
quiz two is there, which is.
10% of your weight age and 20% overall
line assignments is about 15%.
Easy one.
Can we get the PDF copied of these books?
I don't have a copy of it.
I'll see in case anything if I find I'll
forward to you guys.
Yeah.
Customer success, okay.
Customer success is different.
There's a question by Srisha. See,
customer success is basically in a
company like Product Company.
Customer success is not a service company.
It's a customer service.
Success is basically the other one who
makes sure they train the product,
you deliver the product.
to you, help you to train them,
make sure that you become successful with
the product what they give you,
or solution you give you.
They are a small team of people,
they work closely with the customers,
and they make sure that they seamlessly
they adopt to the new solution.
There is a team in any product company,
they have it.
They called it the Customer Success Team.
All right, I'll see what I can do,
Kaushik.
I don't know whether I can get or we can,
I'll forward.
I'm sure you'll be able to find out the
handouts. Just go through that. Inspired,
the good books are there.
Eric Lean Playbook is there.
And there are a few books on the seven
steps of if any.
So I can get the details and forward.
You can just check out all the handouts
it will be there. All right,
and I'll get back to you. Anything else?
Okay, if it is definitely inspired us,
inspired a lot of good books are there,
inspired is there.
I can recommend on the next class with
the proper one so that you don't just
give a wait for a week.
It'll be useful for your career also,
wherever even you don't invest only for
your, for just to finish this course.
Whatever you buy it,
try to use it for your career.
So you can keep it as your anytime
reference book. I'll let you know.
On the with the author name.
Uh, yeah, this is a, I have,
I'm taking one more session, the...
I'm taking one more session on Saturday.
This is for me,
that session starts at one.
I have to finish 10 to 1230, 1030 to 1230,
immediately within half an hour I have to
take the other session.
I'm not having time to prepare.
I may not give a good job and I might not
be able to add value to you guys.
Without preparation, I don't want to come.
I need to spend more time in trying to do
some research when I come for session.
So if it is on Sunday,
this time it will be really helpful for
me.
Okay, great.
Thank you very much for your time today.
I appreciate for taking your time on
Sunday to join this class and hope it was
useful and we can try to add more
examples. Feel free to.
I like the way you people interact and
you share your thoughts.
This is exactly where I need it and I am
enjoying.
being part of your session.
Thank you very much.
So we'll catch up next week.
Appreciate it. Thank you.
Thank you. Bye.